James B. Murphy Papers ca.1918-1950 Mss.B.M956
American Philosophical Society
James Bumgardner Murphy Papers
Circa 1918-1950
Mss.B.M956
American Philosophical Society
15.5 Linear feet
A pathologist and cancer specialist, James B. Murphy spent most of career associated with the Rockefeller Institute (1911-1950) investigating the role of lymphocytes in tuberculosis, x-ray mutagenesis, and the nature of malignant tumors in fowls. The Murphy Papers contains professional correspondence and research notes relating to James B. Murphy's cancer research at the Rockefeller, and information on several of the organizations to which he contributed or belonged, including the American Association for Cancer Research; American Bureau for Medical Aid to China; American Cancer Society; Bar Harbor Medical and Surgical Hospital; Roscoe B. Jackson Memorial Laboratory; Memorial Hospital for the Treatment of Cancer (New York City, ca. 1932-1950); National Advisory Cancer Council; and the New York Academy of Medicine (1923-1950). Murphy helped to develop mobile laboratories for hospitals in France during World War I.
Murphy, James Bumgardner, 1884-1950
Bibliography
Little, Clarence Cook, "James Bumgardner Murphy," Biographical Memoirs of the National Academy of Science 34 (1960), 183-203.
Löwy, Ilana, "Biomedical research and the constraints of medical practice: James Bumgardner Murphy and the early discovery of the role of lymphocytes in immune Reactions," Bulletin of the History of Medicine 63 (1989), 356-391.
Physiology, Biochemistry, and Biophysics Note
Scholars of physiology, biochemistry, or biophysics may find the following items of interest:
Du Vigneaud, Vincent, 1901-1978 Correspondence (4 items) 1947-1948 English
Levene, P. A. (Phoebus Aaron), 1869-1940 Correspondence (3 items) 1918, 1933 English
Lillie, Frank Rattray, 1870-1947 Correspondence (3 items) 1916 English
Loeb, Jacques, 1859-1924 Correspondence (4 items) 1920-1922 English
Northrop, John Howard, 1891-1987 Correspondence (5 items) 1933-1938 English
Van Slyke, Donald D. (Donald Dexter), 1883-1971 Correspondence (6 items) 1918-1940 English
Wyckoff, Ralph W. G. (Ralph Walter Graystone), 1897-1995 ( Located within "Chemists" folder.) Correspondence (1 item) 1927 English
Related Archival Materials note
Additional Murphy Papers are located at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill and at the Archives Center of the Rockefeller Institute.
The APS also houses the papers of Peyton Rous, Murphy's former supervisor, and several other researchers at the Rockefeller Institute, including Eugene Opie, Leon J. Cole, Oswald Robertson, and Harold Amoss.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of James Slater Murphy, 1974 (accession number 1974-1394ms).
Scope and Contents note
The James B. Murphy Papers offer significant insight into the state of cancer research during the critical period of the 1920s through 1940s. As a researcher at the Rockefeller Institute and a colleague of Peyton Rous, Murphy was situated at the center of American medical investigation. Consisting of 15.5 linear feet of correspondence, manuscripts of papers, and materials relating to administrative activities with hospitals and professional organizations, the collection offers a fairly comprehensive perspective on Murphy's research and professional commitments during the most active period of his career.
Murphy's correspondence provides an excellent sense of the networks of researchers in the United States and, to a lesser degree, Britain, concerned with cancer. Murphy was particularly close to Clarence Cook Little, James Ewing (head of the Memorial Hospital in New York), and Ernest Kennaway, and their letters, both in-coming and retained copies of out-going, are filled with candid assessments of researchers, the competing theories on the origin of cancer, lymphocytes, and mutagenesis. The relatively extensive correspondence with Simon Flexner, Herbert S. Gasser (Nobel laureate, 1944), and Edric Smith, among others, relates primarily to administrative matters at the Rockefeller Institute.
Murphy's involvement in professional organizations relating to cancer studies is thoroughly documented, particularly for his work with the American Cancer Society, the Memorial Hospital, the Sloan Kettering Cancer Institute, and the American Society for the Control of Cancer, Bar Harbor Medical and Surgical Hospital, and the Roscoe B. Jackson Memorial Lab. Among other files relating to research animals are several folders labeled "Lathrop Mouse Records."
An unusual and valuable series of letters addressed to Murphy provides a perspective on the experience of cancer patients in the 1920s and 1930s. Filed under "Cancer cures and inquiries" are over 1.5 linear feet of letters from cancer patients, their families, and other interested parties pertaining to everything from their experiences as patients to their theories on the origin of cancer or ideas for cures. In most cases Murphy's replies are included. Other, similar letters are scattered throughout the collection, including a particularly odd letter from a Hawaiian man signed Wah Wahoo.
Biographical/Historical note
A native North Carolinian, the cancer researcher James B. Murphy was born into a medical family. The son of Patrick Livingston Murphy, Director of the Western North Carolina Insane Asylum, and Bettie Waddell (Bumgardner), Murphy was raised in Morganton, N.C., and educated at the University of North Carolina (BS, 1905) and at the medical school at Johns Hopkins (MD, 1909). Drawn by inclination toward research rather than practice, Murphy nevertheless demonstrated particular skill in dissection and in experimental technique. Fresh out of medical school, he obtained a position under the psychiatrist, Adolf Meyer, in New York, and when Meyer was hired at Johns Hopkins in 1911, Murphy was prepared to return to Baltimore.
Florence Rena Sabin, however, suggested that Murphy accept an offer at the Rockefeller Institute to work in the pathology department under Peyton Rous. Rous's recent work on the viral origins of cancer was just beginning to garner wide notice and seemed to harbor great potential. Making full use of his laboratory skills, Murphy provided valuable assistance in demonstrating that the transmissible agent in the cellular extracts remained active after freezing and drying, and he played a similarly important part in demonstrating that embryos did not reject transplanted tissues, as adult tissues did. His work on the role of lymphocytes in regulating immune response was sufficiently out of step with the main currents of immunology at the time that it received little
During the 1920s, Murphy became a nationally prominent figure in cancer research, serving for many years as an officer in the American Society for the Control of Cancer and its successor the American Cancer Society, on the Advisory Council of the National Cancer Institute, and on the Committee on Growth of the National Research Council. He filled similar guiding roles with the American Bureau of Medical Aid to China, the Bar Harbor Medical and Surgical Hospital, the Roscoe B. Jackson Memorial Lab, the Memorial Hospital for the Treatment of Cancer (ca. 1932-1950); and the National Advisory Cancer Council; New York Academy of Medicine (1923-1950).
Murphy died at his summer home in Bar Harbor, Maine, one year after his retirement from Rockefeller.
American Association for Cancer Research.; American Bureau for Medical Aid to China.; American Cancer Society.; Aub, Joseph Charles, 1890-1873; Bar Harbor Medical and Surgical Hospital; Bayne-Jones, Stanhope, 1888-1970; Bloodgood, Joseph Colt, 1867-1935; Bronson, Margaret L.; Casey, Albert Eugene, 1903-; Caspari, Ernst W.; Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944; Chesney, Alan M., (Alan Mason), 1888-1964; Cowdry, E. V., (Edmund Vincent), 1888-1975; Cramer, Charles; Duran-Reynals, Francisco; Dyott, G. M., (George Miller), 1883-1972; Erdman, Rhoda; Ewing, James; Favilli, Giovanni; Flexner, Simon, 1863-1946; Gasser, Herbert Spencer, 1888-1963; Gates, Frederick L.; Goldfeder, Anna; Hogeboom, George; Jacobs, John L.; Kennaway, Ernest L.; Lathrop, Abbie E. C.; Leddy, Percy Allen; Lewis, Margaret Reed; Lewis, Richard H., 1918-; Little, Clarence C., (Clarence Cook), b. 1888; Loeb, Leo, 1869-1959; Longcope, Warfield T., (Warfield Theobald), 1877-1953; MacNider, William de Berniere, 1881-1951; Maisin, Joseph; Memorial Hospital for the Treatment of Cancer; Minot, George Richards, 1885-1950; Morton, John T.; Nakahara, Warso, 1896-1976; National Advisory Cancer Council (U.S.).; New York Academy of Medicine.; Osterhout, W. J. V., (Winthrop John Van Leuven), 1871-1964; Porter, Keith R.; Rhoads, Cornelius Packard, 1898-1959; Rockefeller Institute.; Roscoe B. Jackson Memorial Laboratory.; Rous, Peyton, 1879-1970; Russell, Frederick Fuller, 1870-1960; Sabin, Florence Rena, 1871-1953; Schram, Mildred W. S.; Shope, Richard E., (Richard Edwin), 1901-; Smith, Edric B; Sokoloff, Boris, 1893-; Spies, John W.; Strong, Leonell C., (Leonell Clarence), 1894-; Sturm, Ernest, 1878-1936; TenBroeck, Carl, 1885-1966; Warren, Shields, 1898-; Weed, Lewis H., (Lewis Hill), 1886-1952; Welch, William Henry, 1850-1934; Wilson, Edwin Bidwell, 1879-1964; Zinsser, Hans, 1878-1940; Cancer--Research; Hospitals--New York (State)--New York; Immunology; Lymphocytes; Medical sciences; Medicine, Military; Medicine--Research; Mice as laboratory animals; Pathology; Radiation--Physiological effect; Tuberculosis--Research; Tumors in animals; World War, 1914-1918--Medical care; X-rays
- Correspondence, ca.1918-1950 (Box 1-39)
  - Abbott, Jere
  - Abel, John J
    - World War I
  - Abels, Jules C
    - Singher, Heron O
    - McNeer, Gordon
  - Adair, Frank E
    - McCarthy, Daniel P
    - Adams, James
    - Perlmutter, Julius Jay
    - Adair, Mrs. Marion H
  - Adams, James S
  - Adams, Lester
  - Addison, Kenneth
  - Adrenal Grafting into the Spleen of Normal Rats and Mice
  - Adreno-Spleeno of Leukemia Mice
  - Akers, Floyd D
  - Alderman, Mrs. Bessie
  - Aldrich, Winthrop W
    - Bayne-Jones, Stanhope
    - Olmstead, Bertram
    - Aldrich, Mrs. Harriet
  - Aldworth, Edward L
  - Alexander, Jerome
  - Alfert, Harry M
  - Allen, Douglas Hedden
  - Allen, Edgar
  - Allen, Frederick M
  - Altree, R F
  - American Association for Cancer Research, 1918
    - Woglom, William H
    - World War I
  - American Association for Cancer Research, 1922-1933
    - Woglom, William H
    - Pappenheimer, Alwin M
  - American Association for Cancer Research, 1934
    - Woglom, William H
  - American Association for Cancer Research, 1935
    - Woglom, William H
    - Marsh, Millard C
  - American Association for Cancer Research, 1936
    - Woglom, William H
    - Smith, George M
    - March, Millard C
    - Allen, Edgar
    - Stewart, Fred
    - Smith, George M
  - American Association for Cancer Research, 1937-1938
    - Thibaudeau, A A
    - Woglom, William H
    - Clowes, C H A
  - American Association for Cancer Research
    - Thibaudeau, A A
    - Rhoads, C P
    - Woglom, William H
  - American Association for Cancer Research, 1941
    - Thibaudeau, A A
    - Smith, George M
    - Voegtlin, Carl
    - Warren, Shields
  - American Association for Cancer Research, 1942
    - Thibaudeau, A A
    - Woglom, William H
    - Warren, Shields
    - Smith, George M
    - Little, C C
  - American Association for Cancer Research, 1943-1946
    - Gardner, W U
    - Hooker, Charles W
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science
  - American Association of Physics Teachers
    - Webb, William S
  - American Bureau for Medical Aid to China
    - Tui, Co
    - Lamont, Thomas
    - Meleney, Frank L
    - Vincent, George E
    - Fitzgerald, Alice
    - Bissell, Franklin E
    - Martin, John J
    - Bajchman, Ludwich
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, Jr.
    - Van Slyke, Donald D
    - Chase, Mrs. Julian
    - Barret, Morris K
  - American Cancer Society
    Scope and Contents note
    See also: American Society for the Control of Cancer.
    - Bobst, Elmer H
    - Ripley, James
    - Fish, H D
    - Lehman, Edwin P
    - Adams, James S
    - Binkley, J Samuel
    - Lyman, Arthur T
    - Oughterson, A W
    - Murray, James E
    - MacEwan, E J
    - Johnston, Eric A
    - Little, C C
    - Adair, Frank E
    - Poteat, Douglass
    - Barry, Guy Thomas
    - Miller, Brewster S
    - Teeter, John H
    - Nesselrode, C C
  - American Cancer Society Grant
    - Coombe, Reginald G
    - Weed, Lewis H
    - Adams, James S
    - Jewett, Frank B
    - Nicholson, Hayden C
    - Owen, Philip S
    - Smith, Edric B
    - McGrail, Richard P
    - Petrzelka, Charles
    - Little, C C
    - Weed, Lewis H
    - Tyson, E
    - Spike, J Edward, Jr.
    - Matlack, E Tyson
    - Gasser, Herbert S
    - Murphy, Harry A
    - Poteat, Douglass
    - Hauck, James S
    - Runyon, Mefford R
  - American College of Physicians
    - Means, James H
    - Loveland, E R
    - Warthin, A S
  - American College of Surgeons
    - Crowell, Bowman C
    - Martin, Franklin H
  - American Journal of Roentgenolgy and Radium Therapy
  - American Medical Association
    - Callender, George R
    - Kerr, William J
    - Minot, George
    - Wilbur, Dwight L
  - American Men of Science
  - American Museum of Health
  - American Public Health Association
    - Atwater, Reginald M
  - American Radium Society
    - Skinner, E H
  - American Red Cross
    - World War I
  - American Roentgen Ray Society
    - Waters, Charles A
  - American Society for Clinical Investigation
    - Sturgis, Cyrus C
    - Hayman, J M., Jr.
    - Andrus, E Cowles
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1926
    - Soper, George A
    - Wood, Frances Carter
    - Aldrich, Winthrop W
    - Howe, F Stanley
    - Taylor, Howard C
    - Minot, George R
    - Lake Mohonk Mountain House
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1927
    - Soper, George A
    - McFadden, Josephine B
    - Scull, William Ellis
    - Stone, William S
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1928
    - Soper, George Albert
    - Ewing, James
    - Cullen, Thomas S
    - Taylor, Howard C
    - Wood, Frances Carter
    - Bloodgood, Joseph Colt
    - Gerster, John C A
    - Lakeman, Curtis Edmunds
    - Wood, Susan M
    - DeBevoise, Thomas M
    - Emerson, Kendall
    - Emerson, Haven
    - Greenough, Robert B
    - Brokaw, R V
    - Warren, Shields
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer Publications and Reports, 1925-1926
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer Publications and Reports, 1927-1928
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1929
    - Thompson, M L
    - Bloodgood, Joseph Colt
    - Ewing, James
    - Brokaw, Raymond V
    - Little, C C
    - Mead, Mrs. Robert Gillespie
    - Rigney, Mrs. E H
    - Taylor, Howard Canning
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1930
    - Little, Clarence C
    - Debevoise, Thomas M
    - Greenough, R B
    - Bloodgood, Joseph C
    - Brokaw, R V
    - Strachauer, Arthur C
    - Ewing, James
    - Crowell, Bowman C
    - Wood, Frances Carter
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1931
    - Greenough, Robert B
    - Pancoast, Henry K
    - Ewing, James
    - Little, Clarence Cook
    - Neff, Louis
    - Soper, George A
    - Charlton, H R
    - Baldwin, William H
    - Bilhuber, Gertrude
    - Norton, Mrs. Margaret T
    - Simmons, R R
    - McFarland, Joseph
    - Cullen, Thomas S
    - Russell, F F
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1932
    - Little, Clarence Cook
    - Brewer, Calvert
    - Taylor, Howard C
    - Greenough, Robert B
    - Norton, Mrs. Margaret T
    - Packard, Arthur W
    - Wainwright, J M
    - Horsley, J S
    - Pancoast, Henry K
    - Cullen, Thomas
    - Milton, David M
    - Stewart, Fred
    - Bilhuber, Gertrude
    - Estabrook, Arthur H
    - Simmons, Marian M
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1933
    - Bilhuber, Gertrude
    - Little, Clarence Cook
    - Pancoast, Henry K
    - Minot, George R
    - Simmons, Marian M
    - Smith, Jesse W
    - Greenough, Robert B
    - Charlton, H R
    - Wood, Francis Carter
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1934
    - Little, Clarence Cook
    - Bigelow, George H
    - Fike, R H
    - Ewing, James
    - Harrold, C C
    - Hull, Thomas G
    - West, Olin
    - Campbell, J L
    - Richardson, C H
    - Bilhuber, Gertrude
    - Taylor, Howard C
    - Hektoen, Ludvig
    - Simmons, Marian M
    - Stewart, Fred
    - Hawkes, Mrs. Caroline F
    - Koch, William F
    - Soper, George A
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1935
    - Little, Clarence Cook
    - Greenough, Robert
    - Swan, John M
    - Flude, John M
    - Simmons, Marian M
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1936
    - Little, Clarence Cook
    - Greenough, Robert B
    - Simmons, Marian M
    - Mead, Mrs. Robert G
    - Kulikowski, E
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1937
    - Little, Clarence Cook
    - Greenough, Robert B
    - Findley, Charles
    - Simmons, Marian M
    - Thibaudeau, A A
    - Kennedy, Robert H
    - Gerster, John C A
    - Charlton, Herbert R
    - Wood, Susan M
    - Illig, Marjorie B
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1938
    - Little, C C
    - Reimann, Stanley P
    - Simmons, Marian M
    - Pitts, Herman C
    - Bigelow, George H., Memorial Fund
    - Read, Clifton R
    - Adair, Frank E
    - Ripley, James H
    - Horsley, J Sheldon
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1939
    - Little, C C
    - Chapple, Bennett
    - Smith, George M
    - Simpson, Burton T
    - Read, Clifton R
    - Ripley, James H
    - Hartwell, Joshua A
    - Illig, Marjorie B
    - Hilles, Charles D., Jr.
    - Reid, Mont R.
    - Chapin, Mrs. John R
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1940
    - Illig, Marjorie B
    - Little, C C
    - Reed, Clifton R
    - Wilson, Edwin B
    - Russell, F F
    - Norton, Mrs. George B
    - Little, C C
    - Binkley, Samuel
    - Thibaudeau, A A
    - Smith, George M
    - Rhoads, C P
    - Rigney, Ella H
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1941
    - Little, C C
    - Charlton, H R
    - Sears, Mrs. E C
    - Binkley, Samuel
    - Read, Clifton R
    - Rigney, Mrs. Ella H
    - Ripley, James H
    - Jones, Tom
    - Illig, Mrs.
    - Morrison, Dorothy E
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1942
    - Little, C C
    - Rogers, Edith Nourse
    - Illig, Marjorie B
    - Rhoads, C P
    - Parran, Thomas
    - Schaeffer, A, Jr.
    - Chapin, Mrs. Margaret DeF
    - Fieser, James L
    - Daniels, Jonathan
    - Hilles, Charles
    - Taylor, Howard Canning
    - Wilson, Edwin B
    - Fish, H D
    - Charlton, H R
    - Derby, Richard
    - Schram, Mildred W S
    - Ripley, James H
    - Cloudman, Arthur M
    - Cancer Research
    - Rigney, Ella H
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1943
    - Little, C C
    - Illig, Mrs. Marjorie
    - Schaeffer, A, Jr.
    - Ripley, James H
    - Adair, Frank E
    - Pitts, Herman C
    - Smith, George M
    - Wilson, Edwin B
    - Taylor, Howard C
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1944
    - Charlton, H R
    - Pitts, Herman C
    - Schaeffer, A, Jr.
    - Little, C C
    - Milligan, Mrs. Harold V
    - Cooper, Mrs. Esther T
    - Neff, J Louis
    - Leiby, Virginia
    - Lorenz, Jean
    - Ripley, James H
    - Foote, Emerson
    - Adair, Frank E
    - Perlmutter, Julius J
    - Rigney, Ella Hoffman
    - Spencer, R R
    - Hilles, Charles D., Jr.
    - Lehman, Edwin P
    - Kress, Louis C
    - Gerster, John C A
    - Larson, George B
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1945
    - Fish, H D
    - Larson, George B
    - Freeman, Mrs. C B
    - Neff, J Louis
    - Little, C C
    - Stephenson, C S
    - Carter, John Franklin
    - Milligan, Mrs. Harold V
    - Ketterer, Mrs. Gustav
    - Wilson, Edwin B
    - VandenBerg, Henry J
    - Sacharov, W P
    - Ripley, James
    - Wierengo, Mrs. Elizabeth F
    - Winter, Norman
    - Rhoads, C P
    - Foote, Emerson
    - Smith, E B
    - Charlton, H R
    - Adair, Frank E
    - Jernigan, H C
    - Reinhardt, Anne
    - Procter, Ivan
    - Johnston, Eric A
    - Grant, Niels, Jr.
    - Campbell, J L
    - Bost, Elmer H
    - MacEwan, Edwin J
    - Adams, James S
    - Tucker, Winifred
    - Haggart, William W
    - Murphy, Bradford
    - Pitts, Herman
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer
    (E.B. Wilson Committee)
    - Little, C C
    - Lehman, Edwin P
    - Wilson, Edwin B
    - Pitts, Herman C
    - Charlton, H R
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer - Plans and Correspondence
    - Rhoads, C P
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, Publications and Reports, 1928
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer Publications and Reports, 1929
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer Publications and Reports, 1930
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer Publications and Reports, 1931
  - American Veterans
  - American Weekly
  - Amerop Industrial Company
    - Flexner, Simon
  - Amoss, David A
    - Finney, J M
    - Bloodgood, Joseph Colt
    - Mallony, F B
  - Amoss, Harold Lindsay
    - World War I
  - Amory, Copley, Jr.
  - Anderson, Albert
  - Andervont, Howard B
  - Andrewes, C H
  - Andrews, Donald H
    - Burton, W M
  - Angell, James R
  - Anti-Vivisection Literature.
  - Apolant, A
  - Apor, Emil
    - Diederichs, H
  - Appeals for Funds
  - Appel, Fred W
  - Applications - Weir, John Marshall
  - Applications for Appointments
  - Applications for Appointments, 1939
  - Applications for Appointments, 1940
  - Archbold Fellowship
    - Dazerin, E J
    - Goodnow, Frank
    - Davison, D J
    - Archbold, Mrs. Ann
    - Archbold, John
  - Archer, Vincent W
  - Armitage, Paul
  - Armstrong, Edward McL
  - Arnoldi, T G
    - Embree, Edwin R
    - X-Ray
  - Association Francaise Pour L'Etude du Cancer
    - Herrenschmidt, A
    - Bausse, M R
    - Cosnard
    - Meyer
  - Association of American Physicians
    - Alvarez, Mrs. V B
    - Dornan, William J
    - Means, J H
    - Robinson, Canby
    - McCrae, Thomas
  - Association of Military Surgeons
    - Munson, E L
    - World War I
  - Atkins, Charles D
  - Atkinson, Walter S
    - Koch Cancer Foundation
  - Atwater, Eliot
  - Aub, Joseph C
  - Auer, John
  - Auger, Carlton
  - Austin, J Harold
  - Austin, James A
  - Avery, A T
  - Avery, Mrs. Mary J
    - World War I
  - Baetjer, Walter A
  - Bahson, Agnew H
    - Adair, Frank E., Jr.
  - Bainbridge, William S
  - Baker, H Searle
  - Baker, Julian M
  - Baker, Lawrence H
  - Baltimore Sun
    - World War I
  - Bancroft, Wilder D
    - Flexner, Simon
  - Bandaline, Jacques
  - Banting, F G
  - Bar Harbor Art Association
    - Dorr, George B
  - Bar Harbor Medical and Surgical Hospital
    - Jones, Mary Cadwalader
    - Copp, H C
    - Proctor, William
    - Fraley, Frederick
    - Thorndike, Augustus
    - Dimock, Mrs. Susan Whitney
    - Stowkowski, Olga Samaroff
    - Rodick, A S
    - Hall, Carrie M
    - Lyman, Fred C
    - West, Esther
    - Neal, H V
    - Greenman, Milton J
    - Minot, George
    - Dunham, Mrs. Edward K
    - Pool, Eugene H
    - Keyes, E Lawrence
    - Wisbar, Dagmarr
    - Jones, I Howard
    - Morrison, Charles C., Jr.
    - Dodge, Mrs. Florence
    - Weymouth, Raymond
    - McAlpin, Mrs. D Hunter
    - Dunham, Edward K., Jr.
    - Jay, Mrs. Peter A
    - Cattell, J McKeen
  - Barber, Clarence
  - Barber, Elizabeth B
  - Barber, Thomas H
  - Barber, Whit C
  - Barbour, Harry
  - Bardeen, C R
    - X-Ray
  - Barker, J Ellis
  - Barlow, Mrs. Ernesta
  - Barlow, Sam L M
  - Barnes, L Edwin
  - Barnes, W E
  - Baronaki, Dr.
  - Barr, David
  - Barret, Harvey P
  - Barrett, Morris K
    - Gustavson, R G
    - Voegtlin, Carl
  - Barrows, M T
  - Barry, Guy Thomas
  - Bartlett, Mrs. Franklin
    - Hartwell, John B
    - Sturm, Ernest